[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"1. Sarah Bradford Hopkins wrote two biographies of this historical figure, who used the profits from Hopkins’ books to establish a retirement home in Auburn, New York. This person guided James Montgomery’s forces in the raid on Combahee Ferry and served Robert Gould Shaw his last meal. In 2016, it was announced that this historical figure will replace Andrew Jackson on the twenty-dollar bill. This activist recruited residents of Chatham, Ontario for John Brown’s raid on Harper’s Ferry, but declined to participate herself. For 10 points, name this abolitionist, nicknamed “Moses,” known for guiding escaped slaves on the Underground Railroad. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harriet Tubman [or Araminta Ross] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. A novel by this author ends with the protagonist’s nephew Russell opening the “yellow, unprepossessing door” of the Bethel Independent Mission. The chauffeur Sparser runs over a little girl while the protagonist of that novel by this author is canoodling in the backseat with Hortense Briggs. A character created by this author leaves his job as a bellhop to work at a factory in Lycurgus, New York, where he meets a woman he later kills by smashing a camera on her head. Roberta Alden appears in this author’s novel about Clyde Griffiths. For 10 points, name this author of An American Tragedy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Theodore Dreiser "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"3. The Dirac equation modifies the Schrödinger equation to account for the results of this theory. A prediction of this theory was tested by measuring the relativistic decay of muons in the Rossi–Hall experiment. This theory involves rotations and boosts that make up the Lorentz transformations between inertial reference frames. The foundation of this theory was laid in the year of the Annus Mirabilis by the paper “On the Electrodynamics of Moving Bodies.” This theory, which involves length contraction and time dilation, predicts mass-energy equivalence through “E = mc squared.” For 10 points, name this theory formulated by Einstein, which is contrasted with its “general” counterpart. ","answer":"ANSWER: special theory of relativity [or SR; or time dilation until it is read; prompt on (theory of) relativity; do not accept or prompt on “general relativity”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. An opera by this composer begins with Fortune and Virtue arguing about who has more power over mankind. The words “Lasciatemi morire” are repeated over and over again in a lost opera by this composer. This coiner of the term seconda pratica wrote the aria “Possente spirto,” and composed a cantata that features the earliest known orchestral use of string tremolo and pizzicato. This composer of L’Arianna wrote an opera whose title character schemes with Ottone to overthrow Nero. This man composed the earliest surviving opera that is still performed. For 10 points, name this composer of The Coronation of Poppea and L’Orfeo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Claudio (Giovanni Antonio) Monteverdi "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"5. In order to become the morning star, a god from this myth system slept with his sister and burned himself in a fire. After playing a conch-shell trumpet and circling his kingdom four times, a god in this myth system created humanity by mixing bones with blood. This system’s war god uses a turquoise snake as a weapon and is usually depicted as a hummingbird. Child sacrifices were performed to appease this myth system’s rain god Tlaloc. This myth system’s wind god took the form of a plumed serpent and was worshipped in the city of Tlatelolco [“tlah-teh-LOHL-ko”]. For 10 points, name this myth system whose god Quetzalcoatl was worshipped by priests in Tenochtitlan [“ten-OCH-teet-LAHN”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aztec mythology "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"6. One of this author’s characters visits San Francisco to see the preserved head of a man she believes to be her former lover, Joaquin [wa-KEEN] Andieta. Another character created by this author is the daughter of a snakebitten gardener and a servant who chokes to death on a chicken bone. This author of Daughter of Fortune wrote about the prostitute Transito Soto, who saves the life of Pedro Tercero. Poisoned brandy accidentally kills the green-haired Rosa in this author’s novel about the Trueba [“troo-AY-bah”] family. For 10 points, name this Chilean author of Eva Luna and The House of the Spirits. ","answer":"ANSWER: Isabel Allende "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"7. A politician with this surname resigned as Conservative Party leader as a result of the Carlton Club Meeting. As Colonial Secretary, a politician with this surname offered to resettle Jews in Uganda. A politician with this surname was told “in the name of God, go!” by Leo Amery during the Norway Debate. The Locarno Pact was negotiated by a diplomat with this surname whose brother succeeded Stanley Baldwin as Prime Minister. That Prime Minister of this surname declared “peace in our time” after allowing the annexation of the Sudetenland at the 1938 Munich Conference. For 10 points, give this surname of the Prime Minister who was replaced by Winston Churchill. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chamberlain family [or Neville Chamberlain; or Austen Chamberlain; or Joseph Chamberlain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"8. A form of “tribalism” called asabiyyah is discussed in Ibn Khaldun's Muqaddimah, an early text taking a “universal” approach to this discipline. Hegel claimed “the Owl of Minerva” flew only in the aftermath of this concept, which he attributed to the weltgeist, or “world spirit,” in a series of lectures that claim Africa does not possess this concept. Giambattista Vico discussed the cyclical nature of this concept in his The New Science. Thomas Carlyle popularized the “great man” theory of this discipline. Echoing Hegel, Karl Marx claimed this thing “repeats itself, first as tragedy, then as farce.” For 10 points, name this field whose early practitioners included Thucydides and Herodotus. ","answer":"ANSWER: history [accept historiography] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"9. One type of these molecules associates with DGCR8 and the Drosha complex to form a stem-loop structure. This type of molecule is cleaved with the help of the protein Argonaute and the RISC [RISK] complex, which are activated by the enzyme Dicer to modulate gene expression. Another class of these molecules has a cloverleaf-shaped secondary structure and carries specific amino acids to the ribosome during elongation. According to a well-known form of the central dogma of molecular biology, this macromolecule serves as the intermediate. For 10 points, “small interfering” and “transfer” are examples of what type of nucleic acid? ","answer":"ANSWER: RNA [or ribonucleic acid; or mRNA; or miRNA; or tRNA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"0. Rescorla and Wagner proposed an equation to measure the strength of this process, and described how it can be inhibited through the “blocking effect.” The Garcia effect involves taste aversion produced by this process. Extinction refers to the failure of this process, which can be reverted through spontaneous recovery. To study this process, one man invented the cumulative recorder and a namesake box, inspired by Edward Thorndike. The first experiment studying this process used it to make dogs salivate at the ring of a bell. For 10 points, what form of learning central to behavioral psychology comes in classical and operant varieties? ","answer":"ANSWER: conditioning [accept classical conditioning or operant conditioning; prompt on learning] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"1. During this war, black volunteers joined zouavo [“zoo-AH-vo”] units to escape slavery. In thanks for his arbitration of a lingering border dispute after this war, one countrynamed a province after Rutherford Hayes. Six ironclads snuck past the river fortress Humaitá [“oo-my-TA”] in this war, allowing the Duke of Caxias [“cah-SHEE-us”] to capture a capital. After the Battle of Cerro Cora, the losing side’s president was executed in front of his mistress Eliza Lynch. This war began with the invasion of Mato Grosso, ordered by Francisco Solano López. This war killed half of Paraguay’s population. For 10 points, name this South American war won by a coalition of Argentina, Brazil, and Uruguay. ","answer":"ANSWER: War of the Triple Alliance [or Paraguayan War until “Paraguay” is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. How Doth the Little Crocodile was painted by a British artist from this movement who lived most of her life in Mexico named Leonora Carrington. It’s not futurism, but an artist from this movement painted in the pittura metafisica style and often depicted mannequins, empty urban spaces, and trains. A man looks at the back of his head in a mirror in Not to Be Reproduced, a work by a member of this movement who also painted a train emerging from a fireplace. In The Treachery of Images, that artist from this movement depicted a pipe above the statement “this is not a pipe.” For 10 points, name this movement of Giorgio di Chirico and René Magritte, whose works were inspired by dreams. ","answer":"ANSWER: surrealism [or surrealist; accept Leonora Carrington until “this movement” is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eastern Orthodoxy [or Russian Orthodoxy; or Greek Orthodoxy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. The presence of neutral hydrogen in the intergalactic medium may cause the emission spectra of these objects to exhibit Gunn-Peterson troughs rather than the typical Lyman-alpha forests. Maarten Schmidt measured distances to these objects, whose extreme redshift helped refute the “steady state” theory of the universe. These active galactic nuclei are thought to be powered by the accretion of gaseous material into supermassive black holes, leading to massive releases of electromagnetic radiation. For 10 points, name these highly luminous and distant objects whose name is a contraction of “quasi-stellar radio source”. ","answer":"ANSWER: quasars [accept quasi-stellar radio sources before mention; prompt on active galactic nucleic or AGNs until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"5. This character blesses some snakes that “coiled” with “a flash of golden light.” While experiencing a vision of two spirit voices, this character learns that he “hath penance done / and penance more will do.” This character, who has a “long grey beard” and “glittering eye,” recounts how Death and Life-in-Death played a game of dice for his soul. In a poem narrated by the Wedding-Guest, this character brings himself bad luck by shooting an albatross, causing him to lament “water, water everywhere / and not a drop to drink.” For 10 points, name this title character of a Rime by Samuel Taylor Coleridge. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Ancient Mariner [accept The Rime of the Ancient Mariner] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"6. Description acceptable. One of these events involved the death of a man who had participated in Operation Balak by sanctioning arms shipments to the Haganah. The first of these events allegedly induced a fatal heart attack in King Wenceslaus IV, leading to the breakout of the Hussite Wars. Count von Thurn led one of these events against a victim who was later granted the title Baron of Highfall. Protestant pamphleteers countered assertions of divine intervention by claiming that the Catholic victims of the second of these events had landed in a dung heap. For 10 points, the Thirty Years’ War was sparked by what act of throwing people from a window in a Czech city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Defenestrations of Prague [or Second Defenestration of Prague; or Third Defenestration of Prague; accept equivalents that including being thrown out of a window in Prague until the giveaway is read; prompt on defenestrations by asking “in what city?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"7. The Texas Declaration of Independence was signed in a town named for this man located on the Brazos River. A mountain named for this man can be ascended via the Crawford Path, and has the highest recorded wind speed in America. This man is the namesake of a bridge that links Manhattan to Fort Lee, New Jersey, that was closed by Chris Christie during “Bridgegate.” A mountain named for this man is the tallest peak of the White Mountains and the highest point in New Hampshire. His is the leftmost face carved into Mount Rushmore. For 10 points, identify this president, the namesake of a state whose largest city is Seattle. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Washington [or Washington-on-the-Brazos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"9. An architect from this European country was inspired by Buckminster Fuller to design two giant geodesic biomes housing a variety of plants for his Eden Project. An architect from this country freed up the floor space of a Hong Kong bank by supporting its exterior with eight steel masts. That architect from this country designed the five billion dollar Apple Park and added a glass dome to the Reichstag. Renzo Piano designed an extremely tall tapering building called the Shard in this country, which is also home to a building called “the Gherkin.” For 10 points, name this home country of architects Norman Foster and Christopher Wren. ","answer":"ANSWER: England [or Great Britain; or United Kingdom; or U.K] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"0. A character in this play contrasts his “sole reality” with a “game of art” after a machinist accidentally lets down a curtain. After predicting the end of this play, one man describes how the “Demon of Experiment” hides within him. A woman in this play wishes to be called “Amalia,” although she is primarily referred to as “the Mother.” Father attempts to construct a shop by hanging up the actresses’ hats in this play, which causes Madame Pace to appear. This play begins with actors rehearsing the second act of Mixing It Up. For 10 points, name this play in which the Manager loses “a whole day” of rehearsals because of the title intrusive family, by Luigi Pirandello. ","answer":"ANSWER: Six Characters in Search of an Author [or Sei personaggi in cerca d’autore] Tiebreaker. A common method for designing these devices is a graph with two operating lines, an equilibrium line, and a series of stair-steps from the bottoms to the overheads. The output of a catalytic cracker is usually fed directly into one of these pieces of equipment. These devices are operated at -300 degrees Fahrenheit to do cryogenic separation of oxygen from nitrogen. Refluxing liquid drains downward through these devices to enhance the purity of streams coming out of them. Kerosene is one of the “fractions” coming off these devices when they’re used to refine petroleum. For 10 points, name these columns that separate liquids by their boiling points. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this remnant radiation that provides strong support for the Big Bang theory. It is measured through satellites such as DASI [das-see] and WMAP [“double u MAP”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cosmic Microwave Background Radiation [or CMBR] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The temperature of the CMBR is inversely proportional to this quantity, a measurement of the relative expansion of the universe. This dimensionless quantity is symbolized a and is invoked in the Friedmann equations. ","answer":"ANSWER: cosmic scale factor [or Robertson–Walker scale factor] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The CMBR was discovered with a telescope sensitive to microwaves in this lowest-energy region of the electromagnetic spectrum. Karl Jansky pioneered the study of radiation in this region of the spectrum. ","answer":"ANSWER: radio waves "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. A character named after this author engages in a debate over the theology of laughter with William of Baskerville in Umberto Eco’s The Name of the Rose. For 10 points each: [10 Name this South American author of “The Garden of Forking Paths.” Like the antagonist of Eco’s novel, this real-life author was blind and obsessed with labyrinths. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jorge Luis Borges "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Eco modeled William of Baskerville after this Arthur Conan Doyle-created detective, whose relationship with John Watson resembles the dynamic between William and Adso of Melk in Eco’s novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherlock Holmes [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] A retired beekeeper heavily implied to be Sherlock Holmes helps a Jewish refugee find a lost parrot in this man’s novel The Final Solution. This author won the Pulitzer Prize for a novel in which two Jewish boys create The Escapist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michael Chabon (Chabon won a Pulitzer for The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier and Clay) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this ballet by Sergei Prokofiev. It includes a “Dance of the Knights” that Prokofiev later used in the Montagues and Capulets section of his Suite No. 2, titled after the feuding families in this ballet’s source material. ","answer":"ANSWER: Romeo and Juliet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The work of Shakespeare also inspired a Frederick Ashton ballet titled for one of these events. In musical theatre, atmospheric sections focused on dancing are known as this sort of “ballet,” popularized by Agnes de Mille’s choreography for Oklahoma! ","answer":"ANSWER: dreams [or The Dream; or dream ballet] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Christopher Wheeldon, the choreographer of an adaptation of Shakespeare’s Winter’s Tale, is noted for his collaborations with this Moscow-based ballet company. With the Mariinsky Ballet, this company is considered the most prestigious in Russia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bolshoi Ballet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this sport played by Aaron Hernandez and Junior Seau, both of whom may have committed suicide due to the symptoms of CTE. ","answer":"ANSWER: American football "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In 2009, this current commissioner of the NFL issued a rule change forcing teams to bench players who showed signs of head injuries. ","answer":"ANSWER: Roger Goodell "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This current Washington State head coach was fired by Texas Tech after he locked a concussed player in an equipment closet. He popularized the Air Raid offense during his time at Texas Tech. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mike Leach "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this condition that, like castration, was commonly inflicted on political prisoners in the Byzantine court. The Diadochid ruler Antigonus the One-Eyed partially suffered from this condition. ","answer":"ANSWER: blindness [accept equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] During this campaign, the blind Venetian doge Enrico Dandolo helped Isaac’s son overthrow Alexios. The participants in this crusade never made it to the Holy Land, but ended up sacking the Byzantine capital instead. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fourth Crusade [prompt on the Crusades] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] An army of these people had 199 out of every 200 eyes removed after they were defeated by the Byzantines at the Battle of Kleidion. This ethnic group was subjugated by the Byzantine emperor Basil II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bulgars [or Bulgarians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this populist leader of the National Regeneration Movement. He defeated Ricardo Anaya in a July 2018 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador [or AMLO; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Lopez Obrador is the president-elect of this country. With the United States and Canada, this country is party to the recently renegotiated NAFTA treaty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Obrador campaigned on a promise to reform this state-owned Mexican oil company, which Obrador’s predecessor, Enrique Peña Nieto, attempted to privatize. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pemex [or Petroleos Mexicanos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name these optically inactive mixtures made of equal amounts of both types of a substance’s enantiomers. ","answer":"ANSWER: racemic mixtures [or racemates] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This scientist discovered the first racemic mixture, named racemic acid, and resolved it into enantiomers of tartaric acid. This Frenchman also names a process of sterilizing milk by heating it. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis Pasteur "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Resolution of enantiomers from racemic mixtures is commonly done through first converting the enantiomers to these types of isomers. These stereoisomers differ in at least one, but not all, of their stereocenters. ","answer":"ANSWER: diastereomers [or diastereoisomers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this “great” emperor who won the Second Battle of Panipat three decades after his grandfather Babur won a battle at the same location. He founded a new capital for his empire at Fatehpur Sikir ","answer":"ANSWER: Akbar the Great [or Akbar I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Akbar led this Indian empire, whose emperor Shah Jahan built the Red Fort and the Taj Mahal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mughal Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] While Akbar combined Islamic beliefs with Hindu practices, this sixth Mughal emperor reinstated the jizya tax on non-Muslims and executed the Sikh Guru Bahadur. He was given the title Alamgir, meaning “world-seizer.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Aurangzeb [or Aurangzeb Alamgir] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This huntress was the first person to wound the boar, for which she was awarded its hide. Later, this woman was forced to marry Hippomenes after he beat her in a footrace with the help of some distracting golden apples. ","answer":"ANSWER: Atalanta "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This lover of Atalanta killed the Calydonian boar. The Fates predicted that this man would only live as long as a piece of wood; this man died when his mother, Althaea, set the piece of wood on fire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Meleager "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Meleager was the son of Althaea and this man. Artemis sent the boar to attack this Calydonian king after he forgot to honor Artemis at his harvest sacrifices. ","answer":"ANSWER: King Oeneus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this novel about the romances and life of Eatonville resident Janie Crawford. The events of this novel are narrated by Janie to Phoeby Watson as they sit on her back porch. ","answer":"ANSWER: Their Eyes Were Watching God "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In Their Eyes Were Watching God, the changes undergone by this plant symbolize Janie’s awakening sexuality. This plant’s appearance changes from the “snowy virginity of bloom” to an “ecstatic shiver...creaming in every blossom.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the pear tree [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This Floridian wrote Their Eyes Were Watching God. Delia Jones watches her cruel husband Sykes die of a snakebite on his neck in this writer’s short story “Sweat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Zora Neale Hurston "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this Classical era composer of Night Music of the Streets of Madrid. He wrote a String Quintet in E major that is known for its “Celebrated Minuet.” ","answer":"ANSWER: (Ridolfo) Luigi Boccherini "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Grützmacher wrote the best known arrangement of Boccherini’s concerto for this instrument. Boccherini himself played this instrument, whose historical virtuosos include Jacqueline du Pré and Mstislav Rostropovich. ","answer":"ANSWER: cello "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This other classical composer wrote two cello concertos in C major and D major. This “father of the symphony” wrote 106 symphonies, including ones titled Farewell and Surprise. ","answer":"ANSWER: (Franz) Joseph Haydn "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this country whose feudal lords united under the general Skanderbeg to preserve this country’s independence. Later, this country was proclaimed “the world’s first atheist state” by its dictator Enver Hoxha [en-VAIR HOE-jah]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Albania "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] As a child, Skanderbeg was recruited by the Devshirme [“dev-SHUR-may”], or “blood tax,” to fill the ranks of the Janissaries, the slave soldiers of this Muslim empire from which he defected. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ottoman Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Albanian nationalists revere a flag, first hoisted by Skanderbeg, depicting one of these animals. At the 2018 World Cup, Granit Xhaka and Xherdan Shaqiri [jer-DAN shah-KEE-ree] were fined for making this animal’s symbol with their hands. ","answer":"ANSWER: double-headed eagle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this Mexican author of Christopher Unborn. A fictionalized version of Ambrose Bierce goes to Mexico to die in this author’s novel The Old Gringo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carlos Fuentes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Christopher Columbus marvels at “kingdoms naked in the trembling heart” in “Ave Maria,” a poem by an author with this surname. A different author with this last name wrote The Red Badge of Courage. ","answer":"ANSWER: Crane [accept Hart Crane; accept Stephen Crane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The title character of this author’s novel Annie John writes on a picture of Christopher Columbus, upsetting Miss Edward. A woman leaves the West Indies to be an au pair in this author’s novel Lucy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jamaica Kincaid "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this taxonomic classification that is more specific than a genus. ","answer":"ANSWER: species [or speciation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Sympatric speciation is distinguished from this other form of speciation, which occurs when two populations are geographically isolated from each other. ","answer":"ANSWER: allopatric speciation "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This German-born biologist discussed the “biological species concept,” which defines a species in terms of reproductive compatibility, in his 1942 book Systematics and the Origin of Species. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ernst Mayr "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this “accuser” who pressures God into testing Job’s faith. This “prince of darkness” is sometimes conflated with the talking serpent that tempted Eve in the Garden of Eden. ","answer":"ANSWER: Satan [or the Devil] [10] “Greater” and “lesser” forms of magic are practiced by the Church of Satan founded by this person. This author of the largely plagiarized Satanic Bible cultivated Satanism’s public image by shaving his head, wearing capes, and maintaining a black goatee. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This gnostic religion emphasized the struggle between good and evil, sometimes simplified to a struggle between God and Satan. St. Augustine followed this religion as a young man, but later denounced it as a heresy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manichaeism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this concept whose “actual” and “potential” forms were distinguished by Aristotle. Many of Zeno’s paradoxes are concerned with this mathematical concept, that Anaximander referred to as apeiron, or “boundless.” ","answer":"ANSWER: infinite [or infinity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In his magnum-opus Totality and Infinity, Emmanuel Levinas claimed that ethics arise from our face-to-face encounters with this concept. In The Second Sex, Simone de Beauvoir claimed that women were part of this group, contrasted with the Self. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Other "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] A philosopher with this surname documented our philosophical understanding of infinity in his 1990 book The Infinite. Another British philosopher with this surname suggested “good” cannot be defined as part of his naturalistic fallacy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moore [or A. W. Moore; or G. E. Moore] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Spheres and polyhedra can be defined as sets of points in this type of metric space named for a Greek mathematician who wrote the Elements. ","answer":"ANSWER: three-dimensional Euclidean space [prompt on Euclid] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] For this type of set, every point has a neighborhood that also lies in the set. For example, a disk that does not contain its boundary points is this type of set. ","answer":"ANSWER: open set "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] According to a theorem that this mathematician co-names with Bernard Bolzano, every bounded infinite set in R n has an accumulation point--in other words, every bounded sequence has a convergent subsequence. ","answer":"ANSWER: Karl Weierstrass [accept Bolzano-Weierstrass theorem] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this legendary outlaw of the American West who was killed by Pat Garrett. This one-time cattle rustler was nicknamed for his youthful appearance. ","answer":"ANSWER: Billy the Kid [or William Bonney] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Billy the Kid died in this state. This state’s city of Santa Fe is one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the United States. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Billy the Kid’s killing was ordered by this governor who, as a Union general, infamously marched his division down the wrong road at the Battle of Shiloh. He also wrote Ben-Hur. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lew Wallace "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this sort of creature. In another story by the same author, one of these creatures named Josephine is worshipped for her ability to sing. ","answer":"ANSWER: mouse [or mice] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This author of “A Little Fable” and “Josephine the Singer” often featured non-human protagonists in his works, such as the “horrible vermin” that Gregor Samsa transforms into in his novella The Metamorphosis. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Kafka "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In Kafka’s story “Investigations of a Dog,” the title character faints in his own blood after choosing to do this. In another Kafka story, a panther replaces an “artist” who excels at performing this action after he loses popularity. ","answer":"ANSWER: fasting [or hunger; accept equivalent descriptive answers like not eating] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This artist’s block-shaped sculpture Kiss is a famous example of direct carving. He sculpted the Endless Column and The Table of Silence for a World War I memorial in his hometown, Târgu Jiu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Constantin Brâncuși [bran-COOSH] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] William Zorach, a sculptor known for his use of direct carving, was a member of this artistic movement. Guitar and Bust of a Woman were sculpted by this movement’s founder Pablo Picasso. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cubism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Description acceptable. Barbara Hepworth and Henry Moore, who pioneered direct carving in the United Kingdom, often created smooth, curving sculptures with this sort of feature, to which Hepworth often added string. ","answer":"ANSWER: a hole [or negative space; accept equivalents] Tiebreaker. A poet from this country mourned her love Romelio Ureta in her Sonnets of Death. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this home country of Gabriela Mistral. Another poet from this country observes “the night is shattered and the blue stars shiver in the distance” in a poem that begins “tonight I can write the saddest lines.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Chile "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This Chilean poet wrote “Tonight I Can Write the Saddest Lines.” In his collection Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair, this poet laments an impending “hour of departure.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Pablo Neruda "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In “The Heights of Macchu Picchu,” Neruda asks the land to give him “struggle,” “iron,” and these things. One of these geographical features appears in the title of a novel about the alcoholic British diplomat Geoffrey Firmin set on the Day of the Dead. ","answer":"ANSWER: volcanos [or Under the Volcano] (Under the Volcano was written by Malcolm Lowry) EXTRA Answer the following about functional programming, for 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] To be Turing-complete, functional programming relies on this practice in which something is defined in terms of itself, which is contrasted with iteration. It may involve a function calling itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: recursion [or word forms like recursing or recursive function] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Functional programming implements this formal system of logic invented by Alonzo Church. Encodings of lists in this system influenced John McCarthy to develop the language Lisp. ","answer":"ANSWER: lambda calculus [do not accept or prompt on “calculus” alone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This programming feature, in which a function has the same body but has the ability to operate on several different data types, is used extensively in functional programming. ","answer":"ANSWER: polymorphism [or word forms; or parametric polymorphism] Some architects claimed that the choice of this material for one project was “too feminine” and questioned the way it sharply tapered. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this material used for a fountain in Montgomery’s Civil Rights Memorial inscribed with the names of 41 activists. Another memorial consists of this material structured in a V shape, inscribed with over fifty-eight thousand names. ","answer":"ANSWER: black granite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The Civil Rights Memorial was designed by this architect, who won the commission to design Washington D.C’s Vietnam War Memorial at the age of twenty-one. ","answer":"ANSWER: Maya Lin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Maya Lin’s sculpture The Women’s Table depicts a spiral of increasing numbers to commemorate the female enrollment at this U.S. university, her alma mater. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yale University"}]
